hey bestie thanks for joining us today
we thought it was about time to revamp
our acrylic application video
this video is going to be great for the
beginner who is just getting into the
acrylic process
[Music]
okay everyone so i have my model here
with me today and i'm going to start
prepping her nails for acrylic
application
as you can see there's some dead tissue
around the cuticle area and we want to
make sure that we remove that
along with the shine when pushing back
the cuticle you want to make sure
that you are not pushing too hard you
also want to make sure that you are not
going at too deep of an angle because
you can damage the nail
bed and you don't want to do it too
parallel to the nose because you can
slip over the top of the skin and
possibly cut your client
so now that we have those nicely pushed
back you're going to want to grab
a sanding band with a medium to fine
grit
and we're going to use this to remove
the shine of the natural nail
when doing this you want to make sure
that you are kissing the nail
very slightly you don't want to put any
pressure if you want to get more
detailed into removing the dead tissue
from the natural nail
you can grab a tapered cuticle
cleaning bit and this is going to help
you get into the small
channels of the side walls and the
cuticle area
so now that i'm done with the rest of
the fingers we're going to go ahead and
fit the nail tips
when applying the tip you want to make
sure that it's fitted from sidewall to
sidewall
you don't want it to be too large
hanging over and you don't want it to be
too thin
if the nail tip is too small it will
increase the chances of lifting
now when applying the tip to the finger
you want to make sure that you are
putting it
right at the edge where the free edge
would start
you want to make sure that you have
enough of the natural nail beds
so that the acrylic can have something
to adhere to
and it has a proper foundation now that
we've applied the tip it is time
to trim to the desired length and shape
before i use a file on my client i want
to make sure that i properly prep
it when you grab a new file you will
notice that the sides of the file are
extremely sharp
the easiest way to remove this is by
grabbing another file
and running it along the sides
now that i've prepped the file the sides
are going to be dull and they will not
cut my client
the reason why i shape the tip before
applying my acrylic
is because it eliminates me having to do
it at the end of the acrylic application
if you apply the acrylic properly and
smoothly
it will keep the shape that you have
made all right guys now that we have
that on there
and shaped the way we want it to i'm
going to go back with my sanding band
and we are going to get rid of the
sludge here you want this to blend
nicely
because this also increases proper
retention
now i'm going to go ahead and repeat
these steps on the rest of the nails and
i will meet you back here
okay so now that we have all these ready
we are going to start with prepping the
nail for acrylic application
with our dehydrator and our primer first
you want to apply your dehydrator and
you only want to apply it
to the natural nail bed now that that's
dry you want to go in with your primer
and you're also going to apply that to
the nail bed before applying our color
acrylic
i am going to put down a thin layer of
our back to basics
clear powder when applying this bead you
want to make sure that you're not going
all the way to the cuticle area because
when you go into your finished filing
and you file around your cuticle
it's going to file away your pigment
color and you're going to see the clear
underneath
now the reason why i'm putting a clear
layer beneath my color powder
is for when my client comes back and she
wants to change to a different color
all i have to do is file down to my
clear layer
and then we can put a new color on today
i'm going to be using
a new color from the color blend
collection
this color is iconic so really quick i
just wanted to show you all
the consistency of different beads and
what type of bead to look for
so the first bead i want to show you is
a wet bead this is when you have too
much monomer in your brush
and you pick up too much powder you can
see that it's falling off the brush
you're not going to have any control
over this bead
this is also going to give you a very
weak structure now i'm going to show you
guys a dry bead
this is when you don't have enough
monomer you're going to have a very dry
bead
that's going to be hard to get off the
brush and it's not going to
level or flow the way you want it to
to create the perfect bead of acrylic
you want to make sure that you have
enough
monomer in your brush but not too much
when you put your brush into your
monomer if you take it out without
wiping any off
you're going to see little droplets go
down that's going to give you a bead
that is too wet
if you put your brush in your monomer
and you take out all your liquid
that's going to give you a bead that is
too dry so if you put your brush in your
monomer
and you lightly go against the side of
it that's going to give you the perfect
amount of monomer to pick up the perfect
bead
once you have your brush out of your
monomer you want to drag
along the top of your acrylic and that's
going to be the perfect bead that you're
going to work with
the first technique i'm going to show
you guys is the three bead technique
this is going to be using three separate
zones to build up the foundation of your
nail
your first zone is going to be
here and this is the free edge of your
nail
the second zone is going to be the
middle of the nail this is where the
apex and the stress
area are your third zone is going to be
the cuticle area of the nail
okay so we're going to pick up our first
bead i'm going to place it in zone one
and then i'm going to drag it down
towards the free edge this is going to
taper the product down so that we have a
nice
curve at the end of the process you want
to pick up just enough powder
so that you can cover the tip of the
nail
you want to use the body of your brush
to lightly
flatten the acrylic bead
and then pull it towards the free edge
when you're placing your bead you also
want to make sure that you're using the
tip of the brush
to feather in the top of the acrylic
this is going to make it easy for when
you apply the next bead so that they can
flow continuously into each other
so now we're going to do our zone two
i'm going to place this bead in the
middle of the nail and then we're going
to drag it towards the free edge
this bead is going to be slightly bigger
than the first bead that we used
because we want to make sure that we
have enough thickness along the stress
area
this is going to be called the apex of
the nail
another tip i like to use when doing an
acrylic application
is angling my client's nail downward
this is going to help with the flow of
the acrylic
so that it lays nice and flat you want
to remember to
feather the top of the bead into your
next working area
because you don't want to have a sharp
hard line working against you
now our last bead is going to be the
smallest bead and it's going to go into
the cuticle area which is zone 3.
you want wanna make sure that you have
just enough to cover the nail bed
and then you're gonna drag it down into
zone two with the tip of your brush
you're going to ever so lightly walk the
remaining of the bead up into the
cuticle area without touching the skin
alrighty so we're done applying the
acrylic for this nail if you look from
the side you can tell that it is tapered
into the cuticle area
as it goes towards the apex or the
stress area you can see that it's
thicker
this is going to give the nail strength
so that you don't have any breaks
as you get towards the free edge you can
see that it tapers down again
this is going to give that that very
nice curved shape
so now that we're done applying our
color acrylic we're going to encapsulate
with layer of clear
this layer doesn't have to be thick but
you want to make sure that you're
encapsulating all of the color
so this method is a tube bead method
instead of using
three zones we're going to be using two
zones our first zone is going to be from
the apex down the free edge
and then the cuticle area is going to be
our second zone for this technique i'm
going to be
showing you guys another color from the
new color blend
collection this is called daydreamer
it's a very
beautiful purple color and it has an
iridescent shimmer to it
when applying your first bead to zone 2
you want to make sure that you have a
medium to large bead
as you are going to be building up your
apex and you're also going to be
covering
your free edge you're going to place the
bead down and let it settle
and you want to keep the majority of the
thickness at the apex of the nail
while i'm angling her nail downwards i'm
going to use the body of my brush and
i'm going to
drag the bead all the way to the free
edge making sure to taper off
at the end for our next bead we are
going to do the cuticle area you want
just enough product to fill
in this area you don't want to make the
nail too bulky now that we're done with
the acrylic application for our
two bead method we are going to also
encapsulate this nail in
clear again when doing an encapsulation
layer you want to make sure that you are
using
a very small amount of acrylic you don't
want to add
too much bulk to the nail because you
want to keep that slim
clean appearance so now we're going to
go ahead and wait for these nails to dry
and i'm going to
repeat the process on the rest of the
nail a big thing to remember when doing
acrylic application
is acrylic is temperature sensitive if
you are in a very warm environment your
acrylic is going to set a lot faster
than if you are in a cool environment
after we're done applying all of our
acrylic on all the nails we're gonna
make sure they're dry and the best way
to do that is by tapping it
and listening for the clicking sound
so now i'm gonna grab my hand file and
i'm gonna shape the side walls and the
free edge
now because we pre-shaped the nail tip
before adding our acrylic
and we also applied a very thin even
acrylic application
our filing is going to be minimal i'm
going to continue filing and shaping
these nails with my hand file and my
aedral
if you want an in-depth tutorial on how
to do this we'll link a video
in the info bar after i'm done filing i
always like to grab a lint-free nail
white
and some alcohol and just clean the
nails to remove any dust or debris now
if your client is asking for
gel polish or gel art this would be the
type to do it
you want to do it before you put any top
coat on and you want to make sure that
the nails
have a surface that it can adhere to
once you're done with your gel art or if
you want to leave your nails like this
we're ready to move on to the next step
top coat if you're a nail tech that
offers
multiple nail services this is the top
coat for you
it is a non-white top coat and it's also
soakable this is our best-selling top
coat because it is a non-wipe top coat
as soon as the nails are done curing
you're good to go there's no sticky
inhibition layer that you have to wipe
off
today i'm going to be using this top
coat because it is
my favorite
[Music]
it was so much fun hanging out with you
guys today i hope you learned a lot in
this video
if you guys have any comments leave them
down below and don't forget to like and
subscribe
i'll see you guys next time bye